Joe's New School
Trường mới của Joe
It's Joe's first day at his new school.
Hôm nay là ngày đầu tiên của Joe ở trường mới.
He sees a teacher and says,
Cậu ấy thấy một giáo viên và nói,
Hello, my name's Joe. I'm new. I'm looking for my classroom.
Xin chào, tên em là Joe. Em mới đến. Em đang tìm lớp học của em.
The teacher says, Your classroom is over there.
Giáo viên nói, Lớp của em ở đằng kia.
It's nine o'clock and Joe is in the classroom.
Chín giờ rồi và Joe đang ở trong lớp.
It's time for maths.
Đến giờ học toán.
Joe is sitting next to Paul.
Joe ngồi cạnh Paul.
That's strange. My maths book is different, Joe thinks.
Lạ thật. Sách toán của mình khác, Joe nghĩ.
You can look at my book, says Paul.
Bạn có thể xem sách của mình, Paul nói.
It's ten o'clock now and the pupils are in the music room.
Bây giờ là mười giờ và các học sinh ở trong phòng nhạc.
They're playing the recorder.
Các bạn đang chơi sáo.
The teacher says, Repeat after me, please.
Giáo viên nói, Nhắc lại theo cô nhé.
Joe thinks, Oh, this is difficult.
Joe nghĩ, Ôi, cái này khó quá.
At break time, the pupils always play in the playground.
Giờ ra chơi, các học sinh luôn chơi ở sân trường.
It's break time now, but Joe is sitting in the classroom.
Bây giờ là giờ ra chơi, nhưng Joe đang ngồi trong lớp.
The teacher asks, What are you doing?
Giáo viên hỏi, Em đang làm gì vậy?
Joe says, I'm reading the maths book. This maths is difficult for me.
Joe nói, Em đang đọc sách toán. Toán này khó với em.
OK, I can help you, says the teacher.
Được, cô có thể giúp em, giáo viên nói.
It's time for computer studies.
Đến giờ học tin học.
The pupils are in the computer room.
Các học sinh ở trong phòng máy tính.
Joe is looking at a computer.
Joe đang nhìn một chiếc máy tính.
Oh dear, this is difficult for me.
Ôi trời, cái này khó với mình.
I don't understand it, he thinks.
Mình không hiểu, cậu ấy nghĩ.
Then the door opens and a boy comes in.
Rồi cửa mở và một cậu bé bước vào.
Is this class five? He asks.
Đây có phải lớp năm không? Cậu ấy hỏi.
Yes, it is, says the teacher.
Đúng rồi, giáo viên nói.
Oh no, says Joe.
Ôi không, Joe nói.
I'm in the wrong class.
Em vào nhầm lớp rồi.
Joe and the other pupils laugh.
Joe và các bạn khác cười.
I'm in class three, not class five, says Joe.
Em học lớp ba, không phải lớp năm, Joe nói.
Joe goes to his classroom.
Joe đi đến lớp của mình.
Bye, see you in the playground, says Paul.
Tạm biệt, gặp bạn ở sân trường nhé, Paul nói.